# Nicholas Christiny

# Software Developer

# CONTACT

■ nchristiny@gmail.com

nchristiny.com

**?** Chicago, IL

**y** chileannick

in nchristiny

nchristiny

# **SKILLS**

**JavaScript** 

Ruby

SQL

MongoDB

PostgreSQL

HTML5

CSS3

Sass

Git

Rails

React

jQuery

webpack

Mocha

Jasmine

Rspec

AWS

JIRA

# **PROJECTS**

## WATCH THIS!

A film recommendation engine API built on a lightweight Rails-API MongoDB back end and React front end using webpack. Testing performed with Rspec and Mocha.

## CHORD EXPLORER

Single page app deployed to Heroku from greenfield in 8 days. The app shows songs that can be played given the user's choice of chords. It uses JavaScript library Raphaël to render SVG images of guitar chords within AJAX partial views using data from a PostgreSQL back end.

Test-driven developer and empathic programmer experienced in deploying web apps leveraging modern interface libraries.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# APPRENTICE SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jellyvision Inc.

Apple Inc.

Chicago, IL Feb 2016 to May 2016

• Build recommendation engine API with React and Rails 5-API and MongoDB.

- Complete greenfield project creating internal company dashboard tool.
- Test in real-time using Karma, Mocha, Chai, Guard, Rspec.
- Program using SOLID design principles.
- Engage in weekly sprint planning and retrospectives with stakeholders.
- Track progress using JIRA, Agile methodology.

# APPLECARE SUPPORT ADVISOR

Austin, TX

Dec 2011 to May 2015

- Resolve diverse bilingual account and technical issues.
- Train and mentor new advisors.
- Protect customer and company confidentiality.

# ACCOUNT AND TECHNICAL SERVICE REPRESENTATIVE

Austin, TX

Blizzard Entertainment Inc.

Jan 2010 to Sep 2011

- Achieve first contact resolution and key performance indicators consistently.
- Troubleshoot diverse operating systems, hardware and software configurations.

# FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER

Austin, TX

Harte-Hanks Inc.

Sep 2009 to Dec 2009

- Design small business WordPress sites via client-facing consulting, HTML, CSS.
- Deploy using PHP, mySQL, FTP.

## PROCESS ENGINEER - DIFFUSION

Austin, TX

Freescale Semiconductor Inc.

Jan 2006 to Nov 2008

• Utilize statistical process control and Lean manufacturing techniques.

# **EDUCATION**

**DEV BOOTCAMP CHICAGO** 

Web Development 2015

# UNIVERSITY OF TEXAS AT AUSTIN

B.S. Astronomy B.A. Physics

## VOLUNTEERING

## **Dev Bootcamp** · Mentor

Aug 2016 to Current

Provide code reviews and feedback to assist students in computational thinking.

# FreeGeek Chicago Volunteer

Jul 2016 to Current

Refurbish hardware with open-source software and provide community education.

#### **AWARDS**

Apple Inc. RECOGNITION FOR OUTSTANDING CUSTOMER SUPPORT

Apr 2013

Apple Inc. EMPLOYEE OF THE QUARTER NOMINEE

Aug 2012